KIHORO DENIS MWANGI

Nairobi, Kenya | (254) 721941386 | mwangidennis992@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/denis-kmwangi

CAREER SUMMARY

A Software Engineer with over 3 years of professional experience in full-stack development and leading product cycle from conception to completion. Adept at collaborating with diverse teams to develop creative technical solutions for complex software engineering issues.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CodeAfrika, Software Engineer

June 2022 – Jan 2023

- Collaborating with other engineers in API design and development.
- Coordinating with a dynamic software engineering team to develop scalable software solutions
- Collaborating with engineers and interns in an inclusive team-based environment, and identify opportunities for continuous integration and process improvement.
- Creating scalable code for customer business solutions, identifying bugs and product defects, and coordinating with team members to resolve critical technical issues
- Scaling the back-end architecture and codebase.
- Providing peer code review, analyzing and assessing code with an insistence on quality and reliability.

Keypad Systems, Software Engineer

Nov 2021 - May 2022

- Performing detailed analysis of business requirements and developing comprehensive plans defining and scoping project requirements.
- Building and testing ERP and management systems.
- Structuring and developing Rest APIs.
- Upgrading software modules on clients demand.
- Maintaining and testing functional compliance of company software products

Keypad Systems, System Developer Intern

Feb 2021 - May 2021

- Preparing technical documentation on for various internal projects.
- Deploying web-based software's and applications.
- Maintaining and testing functional compliance of company software products.

Qilimo Solutions, Industrial Attachment

Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

- Preparing technical documentation on for various internal projects.
- Redesigning and building user-friendly company website.
- Documenting and writing technical manuals of the systems.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Computer Science

Meru University Of Science And Technology, September 2018 – Nov 2022

KEY SKILLS

- Web design/development with Html, Css, Javascripts, Php, Laravel, Codelgniter, Springboot, ReactJs, Wordpress, VueJs.
- Software development with Java & Python.
- Database design and management with Postgres & MySql.
- API design and development.
- Sms APIs Intergration.
- Payment Intergrations
- Software testing and automation with Jenkins and CI/CD tools
- Cloud deployment and server management (AWS, VPs and Digital Ocean).
- Version control git & Github.
- Scrum
- Software development life cycle

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS cloud practitioner 2021
- Software automation testing 2021
- DevOps infrastructure automation 2022

REFEREES

- Ngeno Victor CodeAfrika Project Manager 0707142565 engenovic@gmail.com
- Brian Mosoti Keypad Systems Project Manager 0704841333
 brianjuniorrasugu@gmail.com
- Simon Nyota Co-Founder Qilimo Solutions and SmartChuo 0721772697 snyotah@gmail.com